Inventory of the Luis Kutner papers
Hoover Institution Archives
Luis Kutner papers
1880-1993
82015
Hoover Institution Archives
304 manuscript boxes, 5 oversize boxes, 1 phonotape reel (128.8 linear feet)
Includes writings, correspondence, legal briefs, and printed matter relating to international civil rights cases, world federation, and attempts to secure international recognition of habeas corpus and due process of law by an American lawyer who was both chairman of the Commission for International Due Process of Law and the World Habeas Corpus Commission. Sound use copy of sound recording available.
Kutner, Luis, 1908-
Access
Collection stored off site; a minimum of two days notice is required for use. Boxes may be requested through Stanford's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To view films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
The Kutner papers were acquired in 1982. Incremental materials in boxes 116 to 240 were added from 1983 to 1993. Incremental materials in boxes 241 to 309 were added in 2011.
Biographical Note
1908 June 9 Born, Chicago, Illinois
1927 J.D., University of Chicago
1930 Admitted to Bar, State of Illinois
1944 Author, The Admiral (biography of George Dewey) (with Laurin Healy)
1948 Author, Fights and Cascades, Moon Splashed, Red Wine and Shadows (poems)
1953 Author, Live in Twelve Minutes (novel) (with W. T. Brannon)
1957 Author, The International Court of Habeas Corpus and the United Nations Writ of Habeas Corpus
1958 Author, World Habeas Corpus: A Proposal for International Court of Habeas Corpus and the United Nations Writ of Habeas Corpus
1961 Co-founded Amnesty International (with Peter Benenson)
1962 Author, World Habeas Corpus
1966 Author, I, the Lawyer
1967 Wrote the first living will
1970 Author, Legal Aspects of Charitable Trusts and Foundations: A Guide for Philanthropoids, The Intelligent Women's Guide to Future Security (also published as How to Be a Wise Widow) Editor, The Human Right to Individual Freedom: A Symposium on World Habeas to Corpus
1972 U.S. congressional nominee for the Nobel Peace Prize
1974 Author, Due Process of Rebellion, How to Be a Wise Widow, and The Trialle of William Shakespeare (three-act play)
1993 March 1 Died, Chicago, Illinois
Scope and Content of Collection
The Luis Kutner papers describe his activities as a lawyer, as chairman of the Commission for International Due Process of Law, and as chairman of the World Habeas Corpus Commission. They consist of writings, correspondence, legal briefs, and printed matter relating to international civil rights cases, world federation, and attempts to secure international recognition of habeas corpus and due process of law.
The materials reflect Kutner's advocacy for the right to a fair trial based on due process of law, his crusade against unlawful arrest and ill treatment of political prisoners, his propagation of the concepts of euthanasia and the living will to uphold the right to die with dignity, and his commitment to saving the environment and protecting marine life.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Commission for International Due Process of Law.; World Habeas Corpus Commission.; Audiotapes.; Civil rights.; Due process of law.; Habeas corpus (international law); International law.; International organization.; Law.; Lawyers--United States.
- Commission for International Due Process of Law, 1958-1981 and undated (Box-folder 1: 1)
  Scope and Contents note
  Background information, minutes of meetings, and press release
- Kutner College of International Law, 1956 (Box-folder 1: 2)
  Budget, charter, and miscellany
- World Court of Human Rights--Statute, undated (Box-folder 1: 3)
- Printed matter on anti-trust law enforcement, crime control, human rights, and personal freedom, 1954-1969 and undated (Box-folder 1: 4)
- Writings by Luis Kutner (Box-folder 1: 5)
  - "Amnesty,", undated
  - "The Rape of Aurora,", undated
  - "A Preface to the Atomic Age,", undated
  - "Due Process of Outer-Space Law: The International Cosmos Court--A Proposal,", 1962 (Box-folder 1: 6)
  - "World Habeas Corpus: Legal Ligament for Political Diversity,", 1965
  - "Due Process of Family Privacy: World Civil Liberty and World Habeas Corpus,", 1967
  - "A World Outer-Space Prison: A Proposal,", 1969
  - "Constructive Notice: A Proposal to End International Terrorism,", 1973
  - "The Emerging United States of Earth: World Habeas Corpus as the Ligament of Unilaw and Global Justice,", 1978
  - "One World: The Universe and Albert Einstein,", 1979
  - "World Habeas Corpus: A Proposal for an International Court of Habeas Corpus and the United Nations Writ of Habeas Corpus,", undated (Box-folder 1: 7)
  - "Plato and Aristotle: Precursors of the Human Rights of World Habeas Corpus,", undated
  - "Habeas Corpus and Other Post-Conviction Remedies,", undated
  - "World Habeas Ecologicus: A Proposed Legal Remedy for the Control and Prevention of Transnational Pollution,", undated
  - "World Habeas Corpus, Human Rights and World Community,", 1967
- Articles about Luis Kutner and note, 1961-1981 (Box-folder 2: 1)
- Writings by Luis Kutner (Box-folder 2: 2)
  - "World Freedom Centers and the World Public Order,", undated
  - "World Habeas Corpus for International Man: A Credo for International Due Process of Law,", 1959
  - "Habeas Proprietatem--Due Process for International Investments: A Prior Consideration for Investments Abroad,", 1963
  - "The World Habeas Corpus: The Legal Ultimate for the Unity of Mankind,", 1965
  - "World Habeas Corpus: A Legal Ligament for Political Diversity,", 1967
  - "Due Process of Family Privacy: World Civil Liberty and World Habeas Corpus,", 1967
  - "International Due Process for Prisoners of War: The Need for a Special Tribunal of World Habeas Corpus,", 1967
  - "A World Outer-Space Prison: A Proposal,", 1969
  - "Habeas Marinus: A Proposal in Ocean Law,", 1969
  - "World Peace and the Rule of Law,", 1969
  - "International Eminent Domain,", 1970
  - Review of Ved Nanda, The Human Right of Individual Freedom: A Symposium on World Habeas Corpus by Luis Kutner, 1971
  - "Constructive Notice: A Proposal to End International Terrorism,", 1973
  - "Plato and Aristotle: Precursors of the Human Rights of World Habeas Corpus,", 1980
  - "The Talmud and World Habeas Corpus,", undated (Box-folder 2: 3)
  - "World Habeas Corpus: Legacy of Mount Sinai,", undated
  - "World Habeas Corpus: Due Process and the Judeo-Christian Tradition,", undated
  - "World Habeas Corpus: Ombudsman for Mankind,", 1970
  - "A Proposal for a United Nations Writ of Habeas Corpus and an International Court of Human Rights,", 1954 (Box-folder 2: 4)
  - "The Case for an International Writ of Habeas Corpus: A Reply,", 1960
  - "An International Writ of Habeas Corpus: Protection of Personal Property in a World of Diverse Systems of Public Order,", 1961
  - "World Habeas Corpus: A Legal Absolute for Survival,", 1962
  - "World Habeas Corpus and International Extradition,", 1964
  - "World Habeas Corpus: The Difference between Civilization and Tyranny,", 1966
  - "World Habeas Corpus, Human Rights and World Community,", 1967
  - "Politicide: The Necessity of an International Court of Criminal Justice,", undated
  - "The Control and Prevention of Transnational Pollution: A Case for World Habeas Ecologicus,", 1977
  - "The Emerging United States of Earth: World Habeas Corpus Ligament of Unilaw,", undated (Box-folder 2: 5)
  - "World Habeas Corpus and the Protection of Jews in Arab Countries,", undated
  - "Habeas Corpus and Other Post Conviction Remedies: Why this Book?", undated
  - "Statute of the World Court of Human Rights,", undated
  - "The Human Rights of Karl Marx,", undated
- Printed matter--World habeas corpus, 1969 (Box-folder 2: 6)
- China, 1974-1976 (Box-folder 3: 1)
  Printed matter
- Tibet, 1959-1977 and undated (Box-folder 3: 2-3)
  Brochures, clippings, note, printed matter, and report
- William F. Cahill, 1977 (Box-folder 3: 4)
  Mailing list
- Vietnam, undated (Box-folder 3: 5)
  Article
- Writing by Luis Kutner, "The Emerging United States of Earth: World Habeas Corpus as the Ligament of Unilaw," and press release, printed matter, and proposal, 1958-1975 (Box-folder 3: 6)
- Printed matter from law journals on the issues of law of the sea, outer space law, repatriation of prisoners and extradition, and other related matters, 1967-1974 (Box-folder 3: 7)
- Miscellany, 1968-1976 (Box-folder 3: 8)
- Lung-Chu Chen, 1969-1971 (Box-folder 4: 1)
  Correspondence, notes, and printed matter
- Taiwan
  - Formosa vs. Taiwan, 1970 (Box-folder 4: 2)
    Memorandum
  - Clippings, letter, and printed matter, 1963-1978 (Box-folder 4: 3-6)
- Tibet
  - Letters, 1966-1977 (Box-folder 4: 7)
  - Hong Kong news release, 1977 (Box-folder 4: 8)
  - Complaint draft, undated (Box-folder 4: 9)
  - Miscellaneous bulletins, newsletters, and pamphlets, 1968-1977 (Box-folder 4: 10-11)
- Printed matter on world habeas corpus, undated (Box-folder 4: 12)
- Clippings and printed matter about right to die and living wills, 1971-1978 (Box-folder 5: 1-3)
  Includes information on Karen Quinlan and Ku Klux Klan
- Euthanasia and living will
  - Article--"Due Process of Euthanasia: The Living Will, a Proposal," 1969, and notes on euthanasia by Luis Kutner, undated (Box-folder 5: 4)
  - Conference materials and letters, 1969-1976 (Box-folder 5: 5-6)
  - Articles on living will by Luis Kutner and others, 1969-1979 and undated (Box-folder 5: 7)
- Justice for Americans Imprisoned and Lost (JAIL), and Justice for Americans Imprisoned in Foreign Countries (JAIFC), 1973-1977 and undated (Box-folder 5: 8-11)
  Miscellany
- Tibet, 1977 (Box-folder 6: 1)
  Paula Kooklin de Wijs
- Society for the Right to Die, 1978 (Box-folder 6: 2)
  Correspondence and miscellany
- Justice for Abandoned Americans and Americans Imprisoned in Foreign Countries (JAIFC), 1973-1978 (Box-folder 6: 3-4)
  Notes and press release
- Printed serials, 1966-1977 (Box-folder 6: 5-6)
- Correspondence
  - Leslie Paffrath and Robert K. Woetzel, 1971 (Box-folder 6: 7)
  - Concerned Americans Committee (CAC), 1969 (Box-folder 6: 8)
- Printed matter on China, cosmic conscience, crime against humanity, and international peace court, 1968-1977 and undated (Box-folder 6: 9-10)
- Correspondence, 1975-1977 (Box-folder 7: 1)
- Commission for International Due Process of Law, 1975 and undated (Box-folder 7: 2-3)
  Letters, press release, and proposal
- Justice for Americans Imprisoned in Foreign Countries (JAIFC) and Justice for Americans Imprisoned and Lost (JAIL), 1973-1976 and undated (Box-folder 7: 4-10)
- Clippings relating to Justice for Americans Imprisoned in Foreign Countries (JAIFC) and Justice for Americans Imprisoned and Lost (JAIL), 1973-1977 (Box-folder 7: 11)
- Miscellany, undated (Box-folder 7: 12)
- Euthanasia and living will, 1966-1971 and undated (Box-folder 8: 1-4)
  Articles by Luis Kutner, brochure, clippings, letters, memoranda, and printed matter
- Jehovah's Witness, 1975-1976 (Box-folder 8: 5)
  Clippings
- Cosmic humanism, 1969-1971 and undated (Box-folder 8: 6-7)
  Articles, clippings, and pamphlets
- Formosan Civil Liberty Defense Fund, 1970-1973 and undated (Box-folder 8: 8)
  Letters, note, printed matter, and miscellany
- German Marshall Fund of the United States, 1979 (Box-folder 8: 9)
  Letters and statement
- International Association of Jewish Lawyers and Jurists--Bernard Katzen, 1969-1979 (Box-folder 8: 10)
  Letters
- Printed matter on disarmament and peace, human rights, and Japan and the United States, 1968-1970 (Box-folder 8: 11)
- International Commerce, 1967-1968 (Box-folder 9: 1)
  Correspondence and printed matter
- International Public Relations Corporation program
  - United States
    - Correspondence, 1963-1969 (Box-folder 9: 2-4)
    - Financial records, 1963-1973 (Box-folder 9: 5-7)
  - Algeria, 1964-1967 (Box-folder 9: 8)
    Annual report, correspondence, and miscellany
  - Arab States, 1967-1968 (Box-folder 9: 9)
    Note and miscellany
  - Heads of States--Afghanistan, Greece, and Iraq, 1967-1968 (Box-folder 9: 10)
  - Germany, 1963 (Box-folder 9: 11)
    Correspondence and press release
  - Clippings and printed matter, 1966-1968 (Box-folder 9: 12)
- Panel on human rights--Luis Kutner's report on human rights, 1966-1967 (Box-folder 10: 1)
  Includes his article, "World Habeas Corpus: The Difference between Civilization and Tyranny"
- Printed matter on arbitration, international law, and world peace, 1965-1975 and undated (Box-folder 10: 2)
- International Law Association, 1970-1972 (Box-folder 10: 3)
  Letters and memoranda
- Lesotho, 1972-1973 (Box-folder 10: 4)
  Brochure, letters, and printed matter
- World Service Authority--World Court
  - Garry Davis, 1972-1978 (Box-folder 10: 5-7)
    Articles, bulletins, clippings, correspondence, and printed matter
  - Mihajlo Mihajlov, 1976 (Box-folder 10: 8)
    Clippings, court orders, letters, notes, printed matter, and telegram
  - Yogi Vhajan, 1975 (Box-folder 10: 9)
    Letters and printed matter
  - Andrew Singh, 1975 (Box-folder 10: 10)
    Clippings and printed matter
  - R. Kent Jones, 1975 (Box-folder 10: 11)
    Announcement and correspondence
  - Charter and by-law, 1975-1976 and undated (Box-folder 10: 12-13)
  - District III, 1974-1976 (Box-folder 10: 14)
  - Correspondence, 1971-1978 (Box-folder 10: 15)
- World Court of Human Rights (Box 11)
  - Correspondence, 1974-1976 (Box-folder 11: 1)
  - Clippings and printed matter on the world court of human rights and establishment of an international criminal court, 1971-1976 (Box-folder 11: 2-3)
  - Miscellany
    - Lyman Hinckley, 1975 (Box-folder 11: 4)
    - Paul Krill/Chua Kee Seng, 1973-1974 (Box-folder 11: 5)
    - Morocco, 1975-1976 (Box-folder 11: 6)
    - Tran Tam, 1975 (Box-folder 11: 7)
    - Treaty-statute, 1974 and undated (Box-folder 11: 8)
    - Kamal Nain Sekhri, 1974 (Box-folder 11: 9)
    - Zakari Ambakwe, 1974 (Box-folder 11: 10)
    - Thailand refugees, 1975 (Box-folder 11: 11)
    - Peter Hall, 1974-1975 (Box-folder 11: 12)
  - John Alexander Sinclair, 1972 (Box-folder 12: 1)
    Human rights trust
  - Clippings and printed matter, 1972-1974 and undated (Box-folder 12: 2)
- World Service Authority/World Court--Garry Davis, 1948-1974 and undated (Box-folder 12: 3-6)
  Articles, clippings, memoranda, note, photocopies, press release, and receipt
- Tibet
  - Correspondence, clippings, printed matter, and miscellany, 1974-1978 (Box-folder 12: 7-8)
  - Lists, 1974-1975 (Box-folder 13: 1-2)
  - Minutes of meeting of Pope Paul VI with the Dalai Lama, 1973 (Box-folder 13: 3)
  - Clippings and printed matter, 1972-1979 (Box-folder 13: 4-6)
  - Memorandum, 1976 (Box-folder 13: 7)
  - Correspondence and related materials on Tibet, 1974-1980 (Box-folder 13: 8)
  - Miscellany
    - Kalden Norbu Dinjsa—Correspondence, 1977 and undated (Box-folder 13: 9)
      Includes 1 photographic print depicting Dinjsa
    - Harold Oram/Lowell Thomas, 1976-1978 (Box-folder 13: 10)
      Clippings and correspondence
    - Prince Peter, 1974 (Box-folder 13: 11)
      Correspondence
    - Green, Wesley and Zoe, 1975 and undated (Box-folder 13: 12)
      Brochures and miscellany
    - International Law Association, 1974-1975 (Box-folder 13: 13)
- Uganda (Box 14)
  - Correspondence, clippings, and printed matter, 1975-1978 (Box-folder 14: 1-3)
  - Miscellany
    - Don J. Pease, 1977-1978 (Box-folder 14: 4)
    - John A. Rowe, 1977-1978 (Box-folder 14: 5)
    - S. J. Luyimbazi Zake, 1978 (Box-folder 14: 6)
    - Alfred B. Bennett, 1977-1978 (Box-folder 14: 7)
    - Tran Tam, 1978 (Box-folder 14: 8)
    - Robert E. Levin, 1977 (Box-folder 14: 9)
    - Ambassadors--Henning Hjorth-Nielsen (Denmark); Ole Algard (Norway); Ingve S. Ingvarsson (Iceland); Anders I. Thumborg (Sweden); and Wilhelm F. Breitenstein (Finland), 1977 (Box-folder 14: 10)
    - Jim Haynes, 1977 (Box-folder 14: 11)
    - Reverend G. G. Grant, 1977 (Box-folder 14: 12)
    - World Association of World Federalists, 1978 (Box-folder 14: 13-14)
    - I. Bagaya, 1977 (Box-folder 14: 15)
    - Ugandan raid, 1976-1977 (Box-folder 14: 16)
- Clippings and printed matter relating to ecological and environmental issues and the whaling controversy, 1959-1977 (Box-folder 15: 1-5)
- Correspondence, 1977-1978 (Box-folder 16: 1)
- "The Genocide of Whales: A Crime against Humanity" by Luis Kutner, undated (Box-folder 16: 2)
- Clippings and printed matter relating to law of the sea and protection of marine life, particularly whales, 1977 (Box-folder 16: 3)
- Church of Scientology, 1975-1976 (Box-folder 16: 4)
  Clippings, correspondence, notes, and printed matter
- World Constitutional Convention, 1963-1979 (Box-folder 16: 5)
  Agenda, letters, press release, and program outline
- World Freedom centers, 1973 (Box-folder 16: 6)
- World Habeas Corpus
  - Mailings and literature, 1959-1980 (Box-folder 16: 7)
  - Fundraising, 1957-1975 (Box-folder 16: 8)
  - Miscellany, 1958-1970 and undated (Box-folder 17: 1)
  - World Habeas Treaty statute, 1965-1976 and undated (Box-folder 17: 2-3)
- Boston Loan Corporation, 1976-1977 (Box-folder 17: 4)
- Domestic violence, 1978-1980 (Box-folder 17: 5-6)
  Clippings, letters, and newsletters
- Clippings and printed matter relating to human rights and security and cooperation in Europe and the world, 1975-1978 (Box-folder 17: 7-9)
- Whales, 1972-1980 (Box-folder 18: 1)
- Uganda
  - John Marqusee, 1977 (Box-folder 18: 2)
    Letter
  - Dilip Patel, 1977 (Box-folder 18: 3)
  - Remigius Kintu, 1978 (Box-folder 18: 4)
    Newsletter
  - Thomas Melady, 1977-1978 (Box-folder 18: 5)
    Clippings and letters
- Equatorial Guinea--Francisco Macie, 1978 (Box-folder 18: 6)
- Clippings and printed matter relating to Amnesty International, human rights and the political situation in the Soviet Union, Tibet, United States, and Vietnam, 1962-1978 (Box-folder 18: 7-9)
- Amnesty International (Box 19)
  - Correspondence, 1973-1978 (Box-folder 19: 1)
  - Al Booth and Associates, 1972-1975 (Box-folder 19: 2)
    Clippings and letter
  - Central America, 1979-1980 (Box-folder 19: 3)
    Clipping, memoranda, and printed matter
  - Miscellany, 1952-1973 (Box-folder 19: 4-5)
- American Physical Society, 1979-1980 (Box-folder 19: 6)
  Includes reports about Edward Gerjuoy, Leonid Brezhnev, and Andrei Sakharov
- Louis Broido, 1968-1970 (Box-folder 19: 7)
  Correspondence and report
- Moise Tshombe case (Box 20)
  - The American Journal of International Law, 1962-1967 (Box-folder 20: 1)
  - Clippings and printed matter, 1967-1969 (Box-folder 20: 2-7)
- Correspondence, 1967-1968 (Box 21)
  - Harry H. Lipsig, 1967 (Box-folder 21: 1)
  - Dante B. Fascell, 1967 (Box-folder 21: 2)
  - Myres S. McDougal, 1967 (Box-folder 21: 3)
  - Charles Philippe Prince d'Orleans, Duke of Nemours, 1967 (Box-folder 21: 4)
  - Marc Schreiber, 1967 (Box-folder 21: 5)
  - Arthur J. Goldberg, 1967 (Box-folder 21: 6)
  - Miscellany, 1967 (Box-folder 21: 7-8)
- Emergency Committee for Tshombe, 1967-1968 (Box-folder 21: 9)
- United States Department of State, 1967 (Box-folder 21: 10)
  Articles, clippings, correspondence, memoranda, and printed matter
- Petition for writ of habeas corpus and trial documents, 1967 and undated (Box-folder 21: 11)
- Fair play for Tshombe, 1967 (Box-folder 21: 12)
  Clippings, printed matter, and report
- Correspondence (Box 22)
  - Hanna Ohman, 1967 (Box-folder 22: 1)
  - Robert F. Kennedy, 1967 (Box-folder 22: 2)
  - J. Darby Bowman, 1967 (Box-folder 22: 3)
  - Tewfik Bouattoura, 1967 (Box-folder 22: 4)
  - Miscellany, 1967 (Box-folder 22: 5-6)
- Clippings and printed matter, 1967-1973 and undated (Box-folder 22: 7-8)
- "World Habeas Corpus: A Legal Ligament for Political Diversity" by Luis Kutner, 1967 (Box-folder 22: 9)
- "World Habeas Corpus, Human Rights and World Community" by Luis Kutner, 1967 (Box-folder 22: 10)
- Articles by others, undated (Box-folder 22: 11)
- Petition for writ of habeas corpus, undated (Box-folder 22: 12)
- Miscellany, undated (Box-folder 22: 13)
- Writings and notes by Luis Kutner (Box 23)
  - "International Eminent Domain"--Draft, undated (Box-folder 23: 1)
  - "Jews in Arab Countries, Reports in New York Times and Facts on Life?", undated (Box-folder 23: 2)
  - "World Habeas Corpus and the Commission for International Due Process of Law,", undated (Box-folder 23: 3)
- Correspondence
  - Madame Tshombe, 1967 (Box-folder 23: 4-5)
  - Moise Tshombe, 1964 (Box-folder 23: 6)
  - André Mignon, 1967-1969 (Box-folder 23: 7)
  - Joseph Feldman, 1969 (Box-folder 23: 8)
  - A. N. Dobrynin, 1970 (Box-folder 23: 9)
  - Leonard C. Meeker, 1967 (Box-folder 23: 10)
  - Jean-Pierre Delacroix, 1968 (Box-folder 23: 11)
  - Harold L. Oram, 1967 (Box-folder 23: 12)
  - Thomas J. Dodd, 1967 (Box-folder 23: 13)
  - Miscellaneous, 1958-1970 (Box-folder 23: 14-18)
- Clippings and printed matter relating to anti-Semitism, extradition, Moise Tshombe, and United Nations, 1969-1970 (Box-folder 23: 19-23)
- Miscellany, 1967-1970 (Box-folder 23: 24)
- Correspondence (Box 24)
  - David Berger, 1969 (Box-folder 24: 1)
  - Joseph G. Feldman and S. Regen Ginsburg, 1969 (Box-folder 24: 2)
  - Alan Cranston, 1969 (Box-folder 24: 3)
  - International Federation of Pilots Association, 1969 (Box-folder 24: 4)
  - Philip M. Klutznick, 1969 (Box-folder 24: 5)
  - Trans World Airlines, 1969 (Box-folder 24: 6)
  - Miscellany, 1969 (Box-folder 24: 7)
- Writings by Luis Kutner (Box-folder 24: 8)
  - Untitled draft on international law, undated
  - "World Habeas Corpus and the Protection of Jews in Arab Countries,", undated
  - "International Law Basis of International Due Process for Prisoners of War" (draft with tentative title), undated
- Clippings and printed matter, 1967-1969 (Box-folder 24: 9-14)
  Affidavits, articles, book reviews, and clippings about Israel and the Jewish community
- Application and petition, undated (Box-folder 24: 15)
- Miscellany, undated (Box-folder 24: 16)
- Israel (Box 25)
  - Correspondence
    - Maynard I. Wishner, 1974-1975 (Box-folder 25: 1)
    - Scott Cohen, 1975 (Box-folder 25: 2)
    - Miscellaneous (including Yehudi Menuhin), 1975 (Box-folder 25: 3)
  - Summary of events, undated (Box-folder 25: 4)
  - Mailing lists, undated (Box-folder 25: 5)
  - Applications, 1974-1975 (Box-folder 25: 6-8)
    Legal records
  - Clippings and printed matter, 1972-1976 (Box-folder 25: 9-11)
  - Miscellany, 1974-1975 and undated (Box-folder 25: 12-14)
- Bolshoi boycott, 1975 (Box-folder 25: 15)
  Letters, printed matter, and miscellany
- Correspondence, 1964-1971 (Box-folder 26: 1-2)
- World Conference on World Peace through Law, Washington, D.C.
  - Correspondence, undated (Box-folder 26: 3)
  - Writing by Luis Kutner--"World Habeas Corpus: A Legal Ligament for Political Diversity,", 1965 (Box-folder 26: 4)
  - Clippings and printed matter, 1965 (Box-folder 26: 5)
  - Miscellany, 1965 (Box-folder 26: 6-7)
- World Habeas Corpus World Conference
  - Agenda, 1968 (Box-folder 26: 8)
  - Correspondence
    - Miscellany, 1967-1968 (Box-folder 26: 9)
    - Henry R. Luce Foundation, 1968 (Box-folder 26: 10)
    - Charles S. Rhyne, 1967-1968 (Box-folder 26: 11)
    - Ford Foundation, 1967-1968 (Box-folder 26: 12)
    - Walter Winchell, 1962-1963 (Box-folder 26: 13)